Guide to the Parliamentary Speeches, Debates, Bills, Etc.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Parliamentary speeches, debates, bills, etc. and other miscellaneous manuscripts and printed documents]
1600-1699
OSBORN fb157
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.21
(1 volume)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb157. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
- Osborn fb157
  - SOMERSET, ENG. CITIZENS.
    - [Petition of the Gentry, Clergy, and Freeholders to Parliament, 1642] (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      1 p.
      Contemporary MS copy.
      Urges Parliament to come to an
      understanding with the King.
      fb 1
  - ANGLESEY, ARTHUR ANNESLEY, 1ST EARL OF, 1641-1686
    - [Protestation concerning Lord Viscount Strafford, 1685 June 3], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      His reasons for voting against the
      reversal of Strafford's attainder.
      LJ, XIV, 29.
      f.2
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1662. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Conference with House of Commons on amendments to the Act of Uniformity, 1662] (Box 1)
      17 p.
      Conference printed in LJ, xi,
      446-450.
      f.3.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [The King's message to the House of Commons, c.1666], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      4 p.
      Contemporary MS copy in the hand of
      John Browne; also a draft copy. The
      King asks for a speedy supply to
      enable him to carry out the war
      effectively.
      f.4-5.
  - YORKSHIRE, ENG. CITIZENS.
    - [Petition of the Knights, Gentry, and Freeholders of the County of York to the King, 1642 May 2] (Box 1)
      The work of "a very small number"
      which opposed the position of
      Parliament. Printed in part in The
      Parliamentary History of Great
      Britain, X, p.481.
      f.6.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1671. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Head of the petition to prevent the growth of Popery, 1670/1 Mar 2], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Draft copy.
      The petition is to be considered at
      a conference with the Commons.
      LJ, XII, 441.
      f.7.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1671. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - "The Reasons which induced the house of Comons to give credit to those three matters of fact in the Clauses of the growth of popery..." (Box 1)
      [1670/1 Mar 10]
      5 p.
      Results of the conference with the
      House of Lords.
      LJ, xii, 449.
      f.8
  - DEVONSHIRE, ENG. CITIZENS.
    - [Report of a petition of the gentry and clergy against the Canons of 1640, and the Etcetera Oath, 1640] (Box 1)
      3 p.
      Contemporary MS.
      Includes a summary of the Devonshire
      objections to the canons and the
      oath, and the text of the petition
      addressed to the Privy Council. Henry
      Bourchier, earl of Bath (1587-1654),
      is reported to have been the first
      signer, and the county's M.P.'s to
      have delivered it. Thomas Wise
      (c.1605-1641); Edward Seymour
      (1610-1688).
      f.9.
  - FALKLAND, LUCIUS CARY, 2ND VISCOUNT, 1610?-1643
    - [unidentified] (Box 1)
      Speaks in favor of the impeachment
      of John Finch, baron Finch of Fordwich
      (1584-1660).
      Rushworth, iv, 139-141.
      f.10.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [The King's answer to the Common's Address against Papists, 1673 Mar 8], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Agrees to put address in execution.
      Cobbett, iv, p.561.
      f.11.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1644. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - "The Exam[ination] of The Lord Chandois" (Box 1)
      [1644 June]
      Algernon Percy, 10th earl of
      Northumberland. Concerns Lord
      Conway's betrayal of Lord Chandos'
      intention of leaving the King at
      Oxford. This is the examination of
      Chandos by a Parliamentary committee.
      See The Parliamentary or
      Constitutional History of England, by
      Several Hands, 2nd ed, 13, p.210-214.
      George Brydges, baron Chandos of
      Sudeley (1620-1655); Edward Conway,
      baron Conway of Ragley (1594-1655)
      Edward Sackville, earl of Dorset
      (1590-1652).
      f.12.
  - FROST, WALTER
    - [Testimony concerning Monsieur Montreuil, c.1646], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph document. Signed by Frost
      and his son. Concerning letters in
      the custody of members of the
      Committee of Both Kingdoms which were
      taken by Jean de Montreuil. Algernon
      Percy, 10th earl of Northumberland
      (1602-1668); Sir Philip Stapleton
      (1603-1647).
      f.13.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1643.
    - [Notes on a conference between the two Houses on the Cessation Treaty, 1642/3 March 10], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS in the hand of Henry
      Elsynge Jr., clerk of the House of
      Commons. On the reverse is a column
      of notes numbered L-6 in the hand of
      John Pym. Alterations of several
      articles made by Lords at a
      conference on the Treaty. See f.34.
      f.14.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Listing of military equipment], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      MS, dated 12 June, no year.
      List of field and mortar pieces,
      "barrells of powder," horses, etc.
      On the reverse side is a detailed
      description of jewels to be pawned.
      f.15.
  - WARWICK, ROBERT RICH, 2ND EARL OF, 1587-1658
    - [Speech in the House of Lords, 1640/1 Jan 26], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      2 p.
      Report on a conference with the
      Commons. Introductory speech by
      Warwick; report of the message from
      the Commons delivered by Oliver St
      John (1598?-1673). Speech mentioned
      in LJ, iv, p.136.
      f.16
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Petition recommending that Thomas Smith be appointed a Commissioner of the Navy, c.1646] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS.
      Petitioner recommends adding Smith
      to the three other commissioners and
      anticipates possible objections to
      Smith.
      f.18
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1630-1685
    - [Message to the House of Commons concerning Sir Richard Temple (1634-1697), 1663 June 16], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Complains of Temple's conduct in the
      House.
      CJ, viii, p.503.
      f.19.
  - WHARTON, THOMAS
    - [The Report by the Commissioners sent into Ireland by Parliament, c. 1646/7 Feb] (Box 1)
      Document signed by Thomas Wharton
      and Richard Salwey (1615-1685). A
      report on James Butler, 1st duke of
      Ormonde's attitudes towards King and
      Parliament.
      f.20.
  - PRATT, THOMAS
    - [Examination and deposition of Thomas Pratt] (Box 1)
      Contemporary documents signed by
      Thomas Pratt with his mark. One edge
      frayed and some text lost. Concerns
      land dispute in Northamptonshire.
      f.21.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1647. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "Reasons why the Lords adhere to their former vote", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [c.1647 Nov]
      About the Four Bills to be sent to
      the King. Addition to the text
      (later cancelled) in the hand of
      John Throckmorton, under-clerk of
      Parliament; marginal note on left is
      by the 2nd earl of Warwick.
      Cobbett, v.3, 925.
      f.22.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [A list of the spiritual and temporal peers in Parliament, c.1661] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS with additions in
      the hand of John Browne. The page
      is torn in two.
      f.23.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - "The names of the Peeres of England according to their creation and Presidency" (Box 1)
      [c.1660]
      Autograph MS.
      Original list made in about 1660,
      but the peers created in 1661 have
      been added.
      f.24.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Extracts from the Journals of the House of Lords 1621 March 20-April 18], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Numbered 5-8; 104 apparently missing.
      Items of interest, including
      procedural questions as well as daily
      business, are arranged by date and
      are numbered.
      f.25.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1660. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "The Answer drawn up by the Lords Committee for church government", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      John Browne. Assertion that nothing
      will be done to prejudice the Church
      of Scotland in the settling of the
      English Church.
      f.26.
  - SCOTLAND PRIVY COUNCIL.
    - [Address to King James II (1633-1701), 1686 Sept 16], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Agreeing to carry out the King's
      wish to grant Roman Catholics
      "ease and immunity."
      f.27.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Notes on Parliamentary rules taken from the records, c.mid-17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Short list of rules and precedents
      concerning penalties imposed on
      peers in the House of Lords for
      non-attendance, departing without
      leave, etc.
      f.28.
  - FINCH, SIR JOHN, BARON FINCH OF FORDWICH, 1584-1660
    - [The report of Lord Keeper Finch to the House of Lords of a conference with John Pym, 1640 April 29], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Draft copy in the hand of John
      Browne. Finch's report of John Pym's
      (1584-1643) speech attempting to
      resolve the differences between the
      two Houses. LJ, iv, 72-73.
      f.29.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [An account of several prorogations of Parliament 1564-1610], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Edges frayed and some text lost.
      Various commissions in Latin
      proroguing Parliament and notes in
      English.
      f.30.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1675. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Bill to prevent the dangers which may arise from persons disaffected with the government, 1675 May], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Bill to require all office holders,
      JPs, MPs, and peers sitting in the
      House of Lords to take non-resisting
      oaths.
      f.31.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "The consequences of the Trade and convoy [at Dover]" (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, c. mid-17th century.
      Document setting forth the advantages
      of the Dover trade, and complaints
      against the Dutch.
      f.32.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Notes on precedents of trials in the House of Lords, mid-17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Arguments against the Commons
      participating or being present at
      such trials.
      f.33.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1643.
    - [Notes on a conference between the two Houses on the Cessation Treaty, 1642/3 March] (Box 1)
      The seventh article of the Treaty is
      given (asking the King to disband the
      armies) and certain objections of the
      House of Commons are listed. See f.14
      f.34.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1695.
    - "A Clause reported from the Bill concerning Oaths", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1684/5 March 20]
      Elsynge Jr. On commissions to tender
      the oath of fidelity.
      f.35.
  - TURNOR, SIR EDWARD, 1617-1676
    - [The Speech of the Speaker of the House of Commons on the prorogation of Parliament and the answer of the King, 1671 Apr 22] (Box 1)
      Contemporary draft copy (incomplete).
      The Speaker requests that the King
      use the supply voted for payment of
      his debts and the King promises to
      do so.
      LJ, xii, 515. Cobbett, v.4, 496.
      f.36.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670
    - [Conference on the Act to prevent malicious maiming and wounding, 1670] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, frayed edges.
      Better known as the 'Coventry Act'.
      Includes a justification by Sir
      William Coventry (1678?-1686) for
      granting special privileges to
      Parliament men. Sir John Coventry
      (d.1681); Sir Thomas Meeres.
      f.37.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1693.
    - "Acts passed both houses and ready for his Majesty's Royal assent" (Box 1)
      [1693]
      List of three public acts and two
      private acts; including Act to
      Attaint James Duke of Monmouth and
      money bills; passed in 1685 and 1693.
      f.38.
  - BRIDGEMAN, SIR ORLANDO, 1606?-1674
    - [Report of his speech as Lord Keeper on the prorogation of Parliament, 1671 Apr 22], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Thanks Parliament on behalf of the
      King for the supplies granted.
      f.39.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691
    - [Accounts and notes, mid-17th century] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, torn. Notes on the
      opening of Parliament and financial
      transactions between "Mr. Coles and
      Jennings."
      f.40.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "The office of gent[leman] Usher of the Black Rod", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [17th century]
      Anonymous MS. In Latin.
      f.41.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [List of peers and bishops, c.1689 or later] (Box 1)
      Perhaps attendance list of House of
      Lords.
      f.42.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1685. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Message of thanks to the King regarding the capture of the Duke of Argyll and the pursuit of the Scottish rebels, 1685 June 22] (Box 1)
      1 p. Contemporary MS copy. Includes the King's message as well as the response of the Lords. Archibald Campbell, 9th earl of Argyll, d.1685. f.43.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1673.
    - "The Conference about the bill against Popery", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [1673]
      List of amendments to the Test Act
      in which there is disagreement
      between the Houses.
      f.44.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1661.
    - [Addition to a bill to pay arrears of officers and sailors, 1661] (Box 1)
      Also includes a few notes on other
      proceedings in Parliament and a
      comment in French on the 'Royall
      Ayde' granted in 1666.
      f.45.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Notes and bills read twice in Parliament, 1621-1628] (Box 1)
      List of bills read in Parliament from
      about 1621 to 1628. The title and
      dates of the bill are given, and some
      entries include notes on whether the
      bill was committed, rejected, or
      passed in the Commons.
      f.46.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Notes on bills thrice read in Parliament, c.mid-17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      List of Acts passed, for the most
      part by both Houses, in the reign of
      James I.
      f.47.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Notes and observations on [statutes] concerning the proceeding in Chancery in cases of equity" (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, 17th century. In
      English with some Latin. Edges
      frayed and some text lost.
      f.48.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Memorandum of the extant Journals of Parliaments] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, 17th century.
      Notes on the Journals of Henry VIII's
      parliaments and on the Journals
      missing since that time.
      f. 49.
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D.1620.
    - [Memorandum on Parliamentary business, c.1606] (Box 1)
      On transferring bills to the Rolls
      of Chancery.
      f.50.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Account of the impeachment of the Archbishop of York and other supporters of Richard II in 1388] (Box 1)
      Notes and comments on the articles
      of the indictment against Alexander
      Neville, Archbishop of York (d.1392),
      Michael de la Pole, Earl of Suffolk
      (1330-1389), Robert de Vere, Duke of
      Ireland (1362-1392), Robert Tresilian
      (d.1388), and Nichol Brembre
      (d.1388).
      f.51.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Extract of parliamentary proceedings, c.1642], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS in Latin.
      Probably in connection with f.51.
      f.52.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - [The petition of the Speaker on behalf of the House of Commons, that the King grant them the traditional liberties, 17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS copy.
      The document includes only the
      petition for the customary privileges
      of the Commons, granted to the
      Commons by the King at the opening of
      each Parliament.
      f.53.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [List of grants made by King Charles II to various people, c.1665], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      List of office holders and pensioners
      including amount of grant.
      f.54.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - "Bills of money and supply granted the King since his Restoration" (Box 1)
      [c.1671]
      Passed by Parliament between 1660
      and 1671.
      f.55.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Notes on transubstantiation, c.17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      In English and Latin. Notes from
      various authorities (Calvin, Jewell,
      etc.) on the Real Presence in the
      Sacrament.
      f.56.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - "The Papists Opinion of the Real presence", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [c.17th century]
      Notes from various authors and
      authorities on transubstantiation.
      Perhaps written during debates on
      Test Act when Browne was Clerk of
      f.57.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1690. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Peers present at the prorogation of Parliament, 1690 Sept 12], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      List printed in LJ, 14, 512.
      f.60.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. SOVEREIGNS.
    - "The Coronation Oath", [n.d.] (Box 1)
      [late 17th century]
      The questions put by the Archbishop
      and the responses of the King.
      f.61.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Catalogue of Parliamentary Journals received by him in April 1638], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Received by Browne upon his becoming
      Clerk of Parliament. The list begins
      with journals of Henry VIII's
      parliaments and includes notes on
      missing journals.
      f.62.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [A portion of a Commonplace Book], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      6 p.
      Autograph, 17th century.
      F.63 is misbound; it should follow
      f.64. Copies of parliamentary,
      religious, and political documents.
      Includes: A speech by John Stubbs
      (1543-1591) given 1579 Nov 3; "Rules
      to be observed in the Translation of
      the Bible", n.d.; "Certain requests
      made by the Lower House of Parliament
      1584 to the Lord Bishops"
      "Directions for the Preachers", n.d.
      f.63-64
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Account of the impeachment of Lord Neville in 1376], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, 17th century.
      An account of the charges brought
      against John Neville, 5th baron Raby
      (d.1388), as an officer of King
      Edward III.
      f.65.
  - CHARLES I, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1600-1649
    - [Patent granting Daniel Bidingfeilde (d.ca.1638) the office of clerk of the Parliament, 1638 Nov], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy in Latin.
      Bidingfeilde died shortly after
      receiving the office and was
      succeeded by John Browne (see f.70
      for Browne's patent).
      f.66.
  - TRULOCKE, THOMAS
    - ALS to John Browne, [n.d.] (Box 1)
      1 p. (folded)
      Land transactions.
      f.67.
  - CREW, THOMAS CREW, BARON, D.1697
    - [Patent granting the office of gamekeeper of several manors to Thomas Rogers, 1671 Oct 3], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      f.68.
  - SPENCER, SIR WILLIAM, BART., 1608-1647
    - [Documents concerning financial transactions between Spencer and James Catelyn, 1640 May 20-21] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copies.
      Spencer's authorization to Sir
      Robert Pye (1585-1662) to pay
      Catelyn 300 pounds; John Brown's
      statement consenting to the payment
      Catelyn's receipt for the money.
      f.69.
  - CHARLES I, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN, 1600-1649
    - [Patent granting the office of Clerk of Parliament to John Browne, c.1638], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Contemporary MS copy, in Latin.
      Followed by a note in English on the
      grant. Browne was Clerk of Parliament
      1638-1649, 1660-1691.
      f.70.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Memorandum on the history and lands of Waltham Abbey and Coggeshall Abbey, England] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, c.16th century.
      Notes on the Founding of the abbeys,
      their lands and prerogatives.
      f.71.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [List of Deeds submitted in lawsuit concerning Sulby Abbey, Northamptonshire], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS. 15th or early 16th
      century.
      f.72.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Legal notes on the Jurisdiction of the court - leet], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Anonymous MS, c.17th century.
      Latin and English.
      f.73.
  - TWICKENHAM, ENGLAND. CITIZENS.
    - [Levy of parish rate, 1647 Oct 4], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Half the page is missing.
      The rate is being levied to maintain
      soldiers charged on the parish, and
      rates due from individuals are given.
      f.74.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Arguments against worshiping the Host], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      This argument against
      transubstantiation states it is "many
      hundreds to one" that the bread and
      wine remains the same and the priest
      cannot change its substance.
      f.75.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of Thomas Davison's bill, 1670 March 30], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Private bill concerning the lands
      and debts of Thomas Davison.
      f.76.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of Shadwell's bill in Parliament, 1670 Mar 26], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Bill to divide the parish of Shepney
      to make Shadwell, England a separate
      parish.
      f.77.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of the Dean of St Paul's bill in Parliament, 1670 Mar 26], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      A bill to enable the Dean to build a
      new mansion house.
      f.78.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of Joseph Primate's bill in Parliament, c.1670], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Bill to give relief to Primate in a
      property dispute.
      f.79.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of Viscount Strafford's bill in Parliament, c.1670], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Private bill concerning the settling
      of one of the manors of William
      Howard, viscount Strafford
      (1614-1680).
      f.80.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of the Beckman family's bill in Parliament, 1669/70 Mar 1], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Printed.
      Bill to enable the Beckman family to
      sell lands to pay debts.
      LJ, xii, 296.
      f.81.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of Sir Francis Fane's (d.1687) bill in Parliament, c.1670], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      A bill to enable Fane to sell lands
      to pay debts.
      f.82.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1670.
    - [A brief of the heirs of the Earl of Downe, 1669/70 March], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Concerns settlement of the estate
      of Sir Thomas Pope, 3rd earl of Downe
      (1598-1668). Mentions Lady Elizabeth
      (Pope) Lee (b.1645).
      f.83.
  - POUTH, DAME ELIZABETH
    - [Petition to Parliament, 1669/70 Mar 2], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Petition to enable her to sell lands
      to pay debts of her daughter and
      son-in-law.
      LJ, v.12, 297.
      f.84.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. COMMISSION FOR CHARITABLE USES.
    - [Decision in the case concerning the trustees in Chipping Warden, Norants, 1670 June 3], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Autograph MS, signed John Garlick,
      Clerk of the Commission. Concerns
      misuse of land by the trustees. See
      f.102 for the decision of the court.
      f.85.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. TREATIES, ETC. 1660-1685
    - [Articles of the treaty with the Dutch, 1667/8 Jan 16/26], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      16 p.
      Contemporary MS copy, several blank
      pages. Negotiations at the Conference
      of Nijmegen. Laurence Hyde, 1st earl
      of Rochester (1641-1711) was the
      English negotiator.
      f.86.
  - SPENCER, SIR WILLIAM, BART., 1608-1647
    - [Land transaction with John Browne and others] (Box 1)
      Draft MS copy with corrections.
      Concerning land sale.
      f.87.
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [The revenues of every bishopric of England and Wales, c.16th century] (Box 1)
      f.88.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1671. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - [Conference with the Commons, 1671 Apr 19] (Box 1)